Every minute in our Andhra and Telangana,
someone is looking at a six-digit hospital bill
.  If this situation comes to us, can
we afford such a bill? To avoid having to pay, we
must have a good health insurance plan in our name with a good company.
So in this video today, I will compare the Hefc Argo Optima
Secure Star Insurance Super Star
plans.
Which of these two is better, which features are
good in both? All this will be explained pin to pin. If
you watch this video, you
will tell yourself which of these two is better.  So
watch this video till the end and if you haven't
subscribed to this channel yet,
subscribe now
.  I am Kaushik, and I am a
former Star Health Insurance Company
headquartered in Chennai.
What is India's first stand-alone health insurance company?  What does Stand Alone
mean? This company only sells health-related
insurance products
.  Moreover, it does not sell term insurance,
car insurance, bike insurance, or home
insurance.
Only sells medical related insurance
.  And they
have a good presence in tier 1 and tier 3 cities, meaning they
have a good presence in tier 2 and tier 3 cities as well, apart from the big metro cities.  More importantly,
this star has tie-ups with many hospitals in tier three cities
.
If we are admitted to those hospitals, a
cashless claim will be made.  We have
100 branches in Andhra and Telangana.
So if you live in tier 2 or tier 3 cities,
this might be a bit of a setback for you
.  Now let's
discuss the main thing about this company, Argo
.  This is a joint venture between the
bank and the Muninchri Group
.
So they have a good presence in tier one cities
.  That is, they have a good presence in metro cities like
Hyderabad, Bangalore, Chennai, Vijayawada, and
Vizag. They are
famous for
providing good digital claims. And besides, this is a
general insurance company. They are
not only in health, they are also in motor and travel.
Do you understand? So they are
diversified in many ways.  It's not like they're
tied up with only medical insurance like a star
.  Now let's
discuss the two main things, client settlement ratio and customer experience
.  The client settlement ratio
for HDFC Bank is 97.  Which is very good should be
more than 95.  The client settlement
ratio means, for example, 100 claims have been received
.  Suppose this company has given 97 claims out of these 100 claims. The
claim settlement ratio of that company is 97. But if you
look at the star, it is 85. The star has 85. Which is
less? So you should observe that
and for every 10,000 claims,
how many complaints are coming for every 10,000 claims?
Who gives the complaints?
If no claim is received, they
give the complaint to IRDI.  So, for
every 10,000 claims, there
are nine complaints against HDFC Argo.  But
Star is getting 50 complaints out of every 10,000 claims.
Similarly, cashless claims are a
cashless claim. Suppose we are
admitted to a network hospital where this company is tied up, then a
cashless claim is
made.  This time just a few hours means that
HDFC Argo will give a claim within a few hours,
if you look at the cashless claim and star, 90% of cashless
claims will
be given within two hours, 90 out of 100
claims will be settled within two hours,
cashless claims, that too only for approved
claims. Remember that
reimbursement claim time
reimbursement means for example, if we are
admitted to a non-network hospital,
then we have to bear all the expenses ourselves, they will
give us bills, we have to take all those bills and
submit them to the insurance company.  If you
submit it like this, HDFC Argo will
refund the money within 7 to 15 days.
Reimbursement will be made.  But if the star
is taken care of, Vita will provide reimbursement within seven days
.  Let
me know in the comments below if you like it or not.  If
the experience happens, we'll all know if it makes sense
.  What's wrong with this? If you look at the 7 to
15 days Star Seven Days and Features
First One, you can see that the
coverage is Sum Insured. If you look at HDFC Argo,
you can see that the coverage ranges from 5 Locks to 2 Cair.   If
you look at And Star,
you can get coverage from 5 lakhs to 1 crore rupees
.  This is where the rider is.   If
we choose that rider,
we can climb to as much coverage as we want, as long as it's unlimited.
They should give it to you, if everything is correct, they will
give it to you. And what is the restoration benefit?
Let me tell you that restoration benefit. For
example, you took a plan with a coverage of 10 lakhs,
were admitted to the hospital, and after taking it, you spent 10 lakhs in the hospital
.  So the
claim has been completed.  Then there
will be restoration.  They used 10 locks, so
another 10 locks will be added
.  This is called restoration. If
you look at the hefc arga, it
will be restored once.  10 lakhs of coverage was spent on
hospital admission and 10 lakhs were
spent.  So it
will be restored for free once again.
You can use 10 more locks.  He
was admitted to the hospital for the second time in the same year.  The second time,
use 10 locks.  So there will be no restoration for the third time
.  It only
happens once.  If you are an add-on, then
this is an add-on.  If the rider
takes that rider, it will be restored as many times as they
want, unlimited times
.  There is no
need to take an unlimited rider on Star Star
.  Unlimited restorations will be performed as many times as needed
.  There is
no such thing as a limit on the number of times you use a restoration.  The best part here is that
both related and unrelated
restorations will be possible.  There
are some related companies now.
Unlimited restoration will be available only for related claims
.  Related means, for example, if you are
admitted due to a heart problem, the cost of 10 lakhs will be spent on
restoration.
Restoration will only happen again if he is admitted again for heart reasons.
Suppose you joined for a different reason, unlimited times are not available. For example, if you are
admitted for the second time due to an accident, you have made a
complete claim of 10 locks.
In that case, restoration will not happen. Unlimited will
not work. But
if you look at the star,
unlimited restoration will
happen for both related and non-related. This is an advantage. And the third
one is pre and post
hospitalization. What is pre and post? For example, if you are
admitted to the hospital for more than 24 hours today, the
health
insurance company will bear the expenses incurred before admission.  The
insurance company will also cover any expenses incurred after admission and discharge.  That's
called pre-post hospitalization.   If
you look at Sohefc,
there is a 60-day pre-order.  So, you were admitted today, right? You have
been to the hospital many times before this and have incurred expenses. You will be covered for the first
60 days
.
HDFC Argo will also cover any expenses incurred up to 180 days after your discharge.  If you look at Star,
before 90 days, HDFC
Argo 60 days, Star 90 days,
and post hospitalization is the
same 180 days. Now the
main thing is the room rent limit. There is no limit for both.
You can check the room of your choice. Some
companies put a limit of only 2000 per day,
3000 only,
but here there is no limit. And
Ayush cover. Both have Ayush cover.
And OPD, Dental OPD means
Outpatient Department. For example, sinus.
I have sinus. I was
admitted to the hospital and had surgery. It was over
within 24 hours.
That means I was admitted for 24 hours. I didn't have to come in the morning. They
gave me a short rest and discharged me immediately.
So, that's what we call OPD.
Many companies say that.  OPD does
not cover the cost. They cover the cost only if you are admitted to the hospital for more than 24 hours
.  The best
part here is that HFC Argo will cover it,
but Star will cover the OPD, the
outpatient department, and
dental. You have a tax problem. If you
don't have it, if there is a small accident, all the
work is done. Many things are
done. So they will
put something else in, they will put something permanent. It has been spent
heavily.
It doesn't work in SoHFC.  That claim won't come, but it's said that
the claim will come in the star.
Now what is copayment?
Most health insurance companies charge a 20%
copay.  For example, if the bill is one lakh,
they won't cover it
because they mentioned that the co-pay is 20%,
so they only give a claim of 80,000, leaving
us with the remaining 20%, i.e. 20,000, from our own pocket.  There is no
problem here.  It's not like there's an option to fight for both
.  They will bear 100% of the cost.
Now, for example, a
person aged 30 years is
taking a policy with a coverage of 10 lakhs.  If he
is taking the Star Super Star plan, he could earn around
9300 per year.  If the same plan is taken by the same person, 30
years of age, with a coverage of 10 lakhs, under the policy of
Yergo Optima Secure, the cost can
go up to 16,700.  Depends upon age and
habits. Is it all the same person?
So, if you look at it in terms of premium, the
star will cost a little less.
Do you understand that this is a family floater and he and
his wife are taking it together?
In that case, you can get up to 13,900 per year in Star Super Star, while if
you look at the same HDFC Arga, it will be
24,300 per year. So of the two, HDFC
Arga is a bit more expensive because the claims are being
given better.  The claims settlement
ratio is also good.  That's not all, in this
video you are comparing two plans
.  There are many plans and many
companies.  If you're wondering how to choose the best plan out of all of these, there's a
platform called Dito Dito where
you can book a free 30-minute consultation
.  Only IRDI certified
experts
will talk to us.  So if we give them all our information,
they will tell us what
will be set up, and they will set up a
good plan for us for free, free, without any charge
.  They don't
call us, they only call us if we book
.  And even after that, they just call and
say, "Take it, take it."  So they are offering good service
.  If you
want it in Telugu too, I will give you the link in the description below and
also in the comments below, so
you can book the call if you want
.  If you mention
Telugu Advisor at the time of booking, it means that
Telugu
people will call you and talk to you.
They will listen to everything and suggest a good plan for you
.  And the
best part here is that if you
take it from them, you will get support.  So
they will help in the future during customer service
.
We can take their assistance whenever we need it.
They have a 4.9 rating.
They have received a rating of 4.9 out of 15,000 reviews
.  If you're thinking of booking, go ahead
.
You can book the call directly by clicking the link provided in the comments below in the description
.  And now let's
see if these are the two waiting period sub-limits.  Let's get to our topic
.  Now, if
we look at the waiting period, the three-year
waiting period for both is the three-year waiting
period for pre-existing diseases.   If
we already have illnesses,
we should definitely tell them that we have these and that
we are admitted to the hospital due to those illnesses, but the claim will not be accepted for
three years because of the three-
year waiting period.  There are some
companies in the market that have a one-year
waiting period.  But
both of these plans have three years.
And some
companies, if
they are undertaking a sinus surgery, will put a limit on it. They
say they will only pay up to 1 lakh as a claim, but it costs you 50 lakhs.
We have to bear that 50.  The
insurance company will bear only one lakh rupees.  Because they
said they would pay one lakh rupees for that illness and
set a limit, but these plans have no
limit.
We should also
note that there is no limit to any illness.  And special benefits: Each
insurance company
has a different benefit for each plan.  So the
special benefit for them is that HDFC Argo has a
secure benefit, which means double cover
from day one, for example, 10 locks, 10
locks coverage. You have seen it.
Why did you choose 10 locks for HDFC Argo Optima Secure?
But you get
20 locks of coverage from day one
.  You can use up to 20 locks
.  Star doesn't have that benefit
.  If you take 1 lakh in Star, it's 1 lakh,
but if you take 2x in Hefc Argo and the
main benefit in Star, the freeze
age benefit means that now, as
our age in each plan increases, the premium will
also increase.  If you pay 8,000 this year, you will have to
pay 8,500 next year.  After that, you have to
pay 9000.  Because as our age
increases, so does the premium
.  But if we look at the star, it doesn't
grow as much as we did when we first climbed it.  For
example, you
can't claim for the first four years, so your
premium will remain the same as it was at the time of taking it out, and it
will increase after you claim.  So this benefit is included
and network hospitals have already
said that if you are admitted to a network hospital, a
cashless claim can be made
.  So, if they are especially
looking for stars, then in our Andhra and Telangana,
there are 2200 network hospitals.  If
you look at the same hefc, it means 1600 1600 is 2200
.  So, in terms of network hospitals,
Star has more
.
There are 500 network hospitals in Hyderabad alone.
Who has only 350 for Star or Argo?
And similarly,
Vijayawada has 90 Star Kihfc
Argo has 70.  And in Vizag, there
are 125, who has Star and HDFC
Sarga has 100.  They have network hospitals in every town and
every city
.  But
in tier 1 and tier 3 cities, most of the star-rated hospitals have
network hospitals.  And
customer support is good for what?
Both are good, so to speak, yes,
digital support is available for both. Yes,
both have digital support.  Branch
support: HDFC Argo has fewer
branches but Star has more.   The
more branches, i.e.
100 in Andhra and Telangana, both have 24*7 claim support
and similarly, claim
tracking is available for both.
We can track the claim in both the portals.
So finally, which of the two is
better? If you need OPD or
outpatient department, you may not be
admitted for more than 24 hours.
Otherwise, you can join the hospital and
get small treatments done. It will cost you. If I
think so, the star will be set for you.
And for dental problems, we will
definitely join for less than 24 hours. For
dental problems,
so in that case, the claim will not come, right?
In the head circuit, so if you want to claim for that too, the
star will definitely be set for you
.  And if you want to have a greater presence offline with branch support,
Star will set you up
.  Because there are many branches, you can
go to the office and ask directly. If
the claim is not received, they will explain it clearly and
may even help with the claim process.  If these three are
your preference, it may be a star set
.  And HDFC Argo, you
want reliability and the claim process should be
smooth.  And if you
want a similar digital experience,
HDFC Argo is the place to be
.  That's not all, even after watching this video,
I am still confused
and if you think that the rest are also good, there are
many of them, then I
have given a simple link, click on the link and
book. They say that they
call for free and there is no
spam, they do not call at all, so
take their advice if you want, take their advice and if you
like what they say, you can
follow them.  Thank you so much.
I hope you liked this content.   If you like it,
say you like it.   If you don't like it,
say you don't like it.
If you want more comparison videos like this, please
let us know in the comments.  Thank you so much
for watching Jai Hind.   The
boss is the boss.